In the previous example,
في المثال السابق،
we saw how we can better our visualizations by removing extraneous elements.
رأينا كيف يمكننا تحسين مجموعة مرئياتنا عن طريق إزالة العناصر الدخيلة.
We can conceptualize this relationship using something called the data-to-ink ratio.
يمكننا تصور هذه العلاقة باستخدام شيء يسمى نسبة البيانات إلى الحبر.
The data-to-ink ratio was defined in 1983 by Edward Tufte,
تم تعريف نسبة data-to-ink في عام 1983 من قبل Edward Tufte،
as the ratio of the amount of ink used to describe
بكونها نسبة كمية الحبر المستخدمة لوصف
the data to the total amount of ink in the visual.
البيانات إلى إجمالي كمية الحبر في المرئي.
In general, the higher the data-to-ink ratio, the better.
وبشكل عام، كلما ارتفعت نسبة data-to-ink، كان ذلك أفضل.
This means that a large amount of the ink in the
وهذا يعني أن كمية كبيرة من الحبر في
visual is being used to actually describe the data,
مجموعة المرئيات يتم استخدامها في وصف البيانات فعليًا،
while low data-ink ratio suggests that you are using
بينما تشير نسبة data-to-ink المنخفضة إلى أنك تستخدم
ink that is added for other purposes rather than describing the data.
الحبر الزائد لأغراض أخرى بدلاً من وصف البيانات
These elements should be removed.
يجب إزالة هذه العناصر.
Let's take a look at an example.
دعونا نلقي نظرة من خلال مثال.
Here, we have two graphs that are representing the same information.
لدينا هنا رسمان بيانيا يمثلان نفس المعلومات.
On the left, we have a visualization with low data-to-ink ratio.
على اليسار، لدينا مرئية مع نسبة منخفضة من data-to-ink.
Notice the extra elements in the visualization that can
لاحظ العناصر الإضافية في المرئيات التي يمكن
be removed including the blue background,
إزالتها بما في ذلك الخلفية الزرقاء،
the horizontal and vertical grid lines,
وخطوط الشبكة الأفقية والعمودية،
and the outer black border.
والحدود السوداء الخارجية.
A large amount of the ink in this visualization is not used to describe the data.
لا يستخدم مقدار كبير من الحبر في هذه المرئية لوصف البيانات.
On the right, we see a visualization with
على اليمين، نرى مجموعة مرئيات مع
the same data but with a high data-to-ink ratio.
نفس البيانات ولكن مع نسبة data-to-ink عالية
The visual on the right only has ink used to
لا يشتمل العرض المرئي على الجانب الأيمن إلا على حبر
directly relate to the understanding of the data.
يرتبط مباشرةً بفهم البيانات.
Comparing both visualizations, the one on the right is not only more
وبمقارنة كلتا المرئيتين، لا يقتصر العرض الموجود في اليمين
pleasing to the eye but it is also much easier to understand.
على إرضاء العين فحسب، بل يسهل فهمه.
When we're building data visualizations,
عندما ننشئ مؤثرات عرض البيانات،
we always want to strive for a high data-ink ratio.
فإننا نرغب دائمًا في السعي للحصول على نسبة data-ink عالية.
Let's go through a few more examples on how we can
دعونا نلقي نظرة على بعض الأمثلة الأخرى حول كيفية
take a visualization with low data-to-ink ratio,
نأخذ مجموعة مرئيات باستخدام نسبة data-ink منخفضة،
or extraneous elements, and reduce it down to
أو عناصر خارجية، وتقليلها
something that is much simpler and easier to understand.
إلى شيء أبسط وأسهل في الفهم.
In this example, we're going to take
في هذا المثال، سنأخذ
a visualization and try to improve its data-to-ink ratio.
مجموعة مرئيات ونحاول تحسين نسبة data-ink.
Here, we have a bar chart representing the number of calories for various types of foods.
لدينا هنا مخطط شريطي يمثل عدد السعرات الحرارية لأنواع مختلفة من الأطعمة.
At first glance, we can see examples of
للوهلة الأولى، يمكننا أن نرى أمثلة على
bad visualization techniques that we've discussed previously,
المرئيات السيئة التي ناقشناها سابقًا،
such as the busy background,
مثل الخلفية المزدحمة
the poor color choices,
وخيارات الألوان الرديئة
and the use of 3D gradients.
واستخدام التدرجات ثلاثية الأبعاد.
Let's walk through it step by step as to how we can simplify
دعونا نتناول هذا الأمر شيئًا فشيئًا لمعرفة كيفية تبسيط
this visualization and increase its data-to-ink ratio.
مجموعة المرئيات هذه وزيادة نسبة data-to-ink.
First, let's remove the wood background from
أولاً، دعونا نزيل الخلفية الخشبية من
the outside and this gray background from the inside,
الخارج وهذه الخلفية الرمادية من الداخل،
increasing contrast and legibility.
مما يزيد من التباين والوضوح.
We can also remove redundant labels such as this legend from the titles.
يمكننا أيضًا إزالة التسميات المتكررة مثل وسيلة الإيضاح هذه من العناوين.
This information is encoded elsewhere.
يتم ترميز هذه المعلومات في مكان آخر.
Now that we have removed the backgrounds,
الآن بعد أن أزلنا الخلفيات،
the heavy borders separating the various elements are no longer necessary.
لم تعد الحدود الثقيلة التي تفصل بين العناصر المختلفة ضرورية.
So let's take those out too.
لذا دعونا نزيل هذه أيضا.
Remember our coloring theory.
تذكر نظرية التلوين التي أخذناها.
We shouldn't use more than one or two colors in
يجب ألا نستخدم أكثر من لون أو لونين في
a visualization unless it's encoded some value in the data.
مجموعة المرئيات ما لم يتم ترميز بعض القيم في البيانات.
The color of these bars don't reflect any differences between the different foods.
لا يعكس لون هذه الأشرطة أي اختلافات بين الأطعمة المختلفة.
So let's remove those colors as well,
لذا دعونا نزيل تلك الألوان أيضًا،
except for the food of interest.
باستثناء الطعام المثير للاهتمام.
In this case, bacon.
في هذه الحالة ، اللحم المقدد.
Great. We've already improved
عظيم. لقد قمنا بالفعل بتحسين
the data-to-ink ratio quite a bit but there's more that we can do.
نسبة data-to-ink إلى حد كبير ولكن هناك المزيد مما يمكننا القيام به.
Recall that 3D graphs including gradients and shadowing can be misleading.
تذكر أن الرسوم البيانية ثلاثية الأبعاد بما في ذلك التدرجات والظلال يمكن أن تكون مضللة.
So let's flatten out these bars and remove the drop shadows to make it more clear.
لذلك دعونا نسوي هذه القضبان ونزيل الظلال الخلفية لجعلها أكثر وضوحًا.
We can also make the data stand out by
يمكننا أيضًا جعل البيانات بارزة عن طريق
reducing the boldness of these labels and grid lines.
تقليل حجم الخط العريض لهذه التسميات وخطوط الشبكة.
If we want to go even further,
إذا أردنا الذهاب إلى أبعد من ذلك،
we can remove the lines entirely and encode the label
فيمكننا إزالة الأسطر بالكامل وترميز
values directly into the bars, like this.
قيم التسمية مباشرة في الأشرطة، مثل هذا.
Comparing the two visualization side by side,
وبمقارنة مجموعتي المرئيات جنبًا إلى جنب،
you can easily see the effect of improving the data-to-ink ratio.
يمكنكم بسهولة رؤية تأثير تحسين نسبة data-to-ink.
The visualization with the high data-to-ink ratio is far more clear,
تُعد مجموعة المرئيات مع نسبة data-to-ink عالية أكثر وضوحًا،
more interpretable, and has all the elements you need for a great visualization.
وأكثر قابلية للتفسير، وتحتوي على جميع العناصر التي تحتاج إليها للحصول على مجموعة مرئيات رائعة.